《行尸走肉》
能进来吗
May I?
你的那…
That was, uh…
那段发言太棒了
that was quite a speech you gave.
危难关头 群众正需要听到这些
Exactly what these people needed to hear.
那监狱那边呢
What about the prison?
只要他们不进攻 就相安无事
As long as they leave us alone, we have no problem.
- 你不会报复吧 - 不会
- So no retaliation? - No.
报复又有何用
What would that get us?
我要去看他们
I need to go see them.
我本希望能改变这地方
I thought this place could be something else, you know?
使它变得更好
Something better.
但我不够格 全搞砸了
I wasn't up to the challenge and I screwed it up.
我做了很多错事
I've done some terrible things.
我不是当领导的料
I'm not fit to lead these people.
但你是
But you are.
群众不该活在恐惧中
They don't need to be terrorized.
尤其不该惧怕自己的领导
Certainly not by their own leader.
你是要让位吗
So you're abdicating?
我真以为
You know, I really believed.
只要保女儿一条命
if I kept her alive long enough,
米尔顿就会找到…
Milton would find a…
我需要点时间…
I just need time…
来重整旗鼓
to get myself together.
你是想让我暂时代替你
So you want me to fill in for you?
除了你还有谁 米尔顿 马丁内斯吗
Who else can? Milton? Martinez?
如果你要选择站在监狱那边 我可以理解
If you choose your friends in the prison, I'd understand.
但镇民需要你
But these people need you.
我…
I…
我们需要你
We need you.
这鬼地方除了蚊子和蚂蚁就没别的了
There ain't nothing out here but mosquitoes and ants.
耐心点 老弟
Patience, little brother.
我们迟早
Sooner or later,
会逮着松鼠
a squirrel is bound to scurry across your path.
耗不起啊 食物不够
Even so, that ain't much food.
总比没有好
More than nothing.
还不如去岔道边
I'd have better luck going through one of them houses.
那几个屋子找找
we passed back on the turnoff.
是你的新朋友教你的吗
Is that what your new friends taught you? Hmm?
如何掠夺
How to loot for booty?
我们在这耗了好几个小时了
We've been at it for hours.
还不如找条小溪逮几条鱼呢
Why don't we find a stream, try to look for some fish?
我觉得你是想把我带回路上去 老兄
I think you're just trying to lead me back to the road, man.
- 带我去监狱 - 那有住的地方
- Get me over to that prison. - They got shelter.
有吃的 还有尿壶可以用
Food. A pot to piss in.
也许不是个坏主意
Might not be a bad idea.
对你来说 也许是吧
For you, maybe.
对我来说 可不是什么好去处
Ain't gonna be no damn party for me.
相处需要过程
Everyone will get used to each other.
他们都死定了
They're all dead.
去那也没什么区别
Makes no difference.
你怎么能这么肯定
How can you be so sure?
现在总督没准正开乔迁派对呢
Right about now he's probably hosting a housewarming party.
而你那伙人的尸体已被他埋在脚下
where's he gonna bury what's left of your pals.
我们去钓点鱼吧
Let's hook some fish.
走吧
Come on.
好了
Right.
你说你是在这里发现泰尔西他们的吗
Now you said you found Tyreese's group here?
- 对 - 我们加固过这里
- Yeah. - We secured this.
他说他们是从这里进来的
He thought he came through here.
也就是说还有其他缺口
Means there's another breach.
好吧
Okay.
监狱整个正面都不安全
The whole front of the prison is unsecure.
如果行尸进来
If walkers just strolled in,
我们就成了那群全副武装的人的盘中餐了
then it's gonna be cake for a group of armed men.
怎么能肯定他一定会来攻击我们呢
Why are we even so sure he's going to attack?
也许你把他吓跑了呢
Maybe you scared him off.
他有一面墙的鱼缸 装满了脑袋
He had fish tanks full of heads.
有行尸的也有人的 当做自己的战利品
Walkers and humans. Trophies.
他肯定会来的
He's coming.
- 我们应该现在就去杀他 - 什么
- We should hit him now. - What?
他不会预料到的
He won't be expecting it.
我们偷偷溜回去 给他来一枪
We'll sneak back in and put a bullet in his head.
我们不是刺客
We're not assassins.
你知道他公寓的位置
You know where his apartment is.
咱俩今晚就能了结此事
You and I could end this tonight.
我自己动手
I'll do it myself.
好吧
Okay.
上次他没有防备
He didn't know you were coming last time.
看看发生了什么
and look what happened.
你差点没命了
You were almost killed.
达里尔被抓住了
Daryl was captured.
你和玛姬差点被处决
And you and Maggie were almost executed.
你阻止不了我
You can't stop me.
瑞克绝对不会允许的
Rick would never allow this.
你觉得他有权对我说三道四吗
You really think he's in any position to make that choice?
你好好想想 T仔在这没了命
Think this through clearly. T-Dog lost his life here.
洛莉也是 还有原来监狱那帮人
Lori, too. The men that were here.
不应该再有更多杀戮了
It isn't worth any more killing.
我们还在等什么 如果他真的要来了
What are we waiting for? If he's really on his way,
我们现在就应该离开这
we should be out of here by now.
- 然后去哪 - 我们整个冬天都住在路上
- And go where? - We lived on the road all winter.
但那时候你双腿健全
Back when you had two legs.
也没有婴儿哭喊吸引行尸
and we didn't have a baby crying for walkers every four hours.
我们不能坐以待毙
We can't stay here.
我们不能逃
We can't run.
好吧 我们不走
All right. We'll stay put.
我们要坚守这里
We're gonna defend this place.
抵抗到底
We're making a stand.
卡尔 我们去趟坟墓
Carl, you and I will go down to the tombs.
找到缺口在哪里
We need to figure out where the breach is.
- 收到 - 需要帮忙吗
- You got it. - You'll need some help.
不 你留在这里 以防万一
No, in case anything happens, I need you out here.
没人在放哨吗
Who's on watch?
见鬼
Damn it.
阿尔法波
Alpha waves.
我试着进入冥想状态
I was trying to induce a meditative state.
我最近心神不宁
I've been having trouble…
你的电池 在这里
your battery, it's over here.
没错 撑住 中头彩了
Yeah, you're holding. Look at this jackpot.
你的贡献一直很大
You've been invaluable.
你想留下吗
Do you intend to stay?
我压根没想过离开
Leaving's never crossed my mind.
很好
Good.
我就指望着你了 不仅仅为了你的
'Cause I count on you. And not just for your…
你的专业知识
your expertise.
我还把你当朋友
But I consider you a friend.
我 谢谢你
I… thank you.
我把你
I feel…
也当朋友
me, too.
我曾指望过莫尔
I counted on Merle as well.
马丁内斯 他是一名优秀的士兵
Martinez, he's a good soldier.
如果我需要 他会帮我挡枪子
He'd take a bullet if I needed him to.
你会吗
Would you?
我也会
I would.
当然
Yes.
安德莉亚呢
And Andrea?
我不知道她到底忠于哪边
I'm not sure where her loyalties lie.
我能理解 以她和莫尔的渊源
I can see how her previous affiliation with Merle,
不管他们关系如何
no matter how contentious it was,
总会令人产生怀疑
could cause doubt.
你帮我密切关注她
You keep tabs on her for me.
没问题
Of course.
马丁内斯在哪里
Where's Martinez?
我不知道
I don't know.
你看到他离开了吗
Did you see him leave?
是的
Yeah.
他跟谁在一起
Who was he with?
凯伦 没关系的 你可以告诉我
Karen, it's okay. You can tell me.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
米尔顿
Milton.
米尔顿 等等
Milton, stop!
你吓到我了
You startled me.
他在哪里
Where is he?
你问谁啊
Where's who?
总督
The Governor.
他貌似出去了
He's out on a run?
你这是肯定句还是疑问句
Is that an answer or a question?
我不太确定他身在何方
I'm not sure… where he is.
不是在和你模棱两可
I mean, not whether it was a question or an answer.
- 当然是肯定句 - 他出去干什么了
- It was an answer. - A run meaning what specifically?
很有可能是去搜集补给
Supplies would be a safe bet.
我们库存不足
We were wiped out.
米尔顿 我的问题很清楚
Milton, I want you to give me a specic answer.
也请你回答得清楚些
to a specific question.
总督在哪儿
Where's the Governor?
貌似出去了
On a run?
我肯定他很快会回来的
You know, I bet he'll be back soon.
如果你担心他的话 他没事的
I'm sure he's okay, if that's what you're worried about.
锅炉房外的墓地又被行尸占领了
The tombs outside the boiler room are overrun again.
我们已经清理过那里了啊
That whole section had been cleared.
有行尸源源不断的涌入
It's a steady stream of walkers.
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting time.
总督应该已经出发了
The Governor is supposedly on the way.
而我们还在对付行尸
and we're stuck in here with walkers.
进退维谷啊
Trapped between a rock and a hard place.
我最后说一次 我们不能逃跑
For the last time, running is not an option.
格伦 如果墓地满是行尸
Glenn, if the tombs have filled up again,
它们迟早会涌进来的
it may just be a matter of time before they push in here.
围栏支撑不住它们也会进来
Or until some fence gives way.
万一有尸群路过呢
What if one of them herds is passing through?
或者干脆住下了
Or settled?
就凭我们几个可对付不了啊
Can't handle that with just the few of us.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 我们得
All right, we need…
我们得去看看监狱的另一边
we just need to scout the far side of the prison.
- 查明情况 - 你要去吗
- Find out what's going on. - You're going out there?
- 开车 快去快回 - 我开车
- Take a car and make it quick. - I'll drive.
不 你留下来 帮忙设防
No, you stay here. Help with the fortifications.
我带玛姬去
I'll take Maggie.
你确定她愿意吗
You sure she's up to that?
你去哪儿了
Where have you been?
我们得查明行尸是怎么进入墓地的
We need to find out how the walkers are getting into the tombs.
你想谈谈那件事吗
Are we gonna talk about this?
玛姬 你需要解开心结
Maggie, you need to talk about it.
我吗 是你需要吧
I do? Or you do?
- 什么意思 - 你想让我说什么
- What does that mean? - What do you want me to say?
你想让我说 他扒光了我
You want me to say he made me get naked.
然后让我站在他面前吗
and stand in front of him?
他走到我背后
He came up behind me.
身体贴着我
Pushed himself against me.
摸遍了我全身
Put his hands all over me.
他按下我的头 把我推到桌上
He slammed my head down and bent me over a table.
他有没有
Did he…
强奸我吗
Rape me?
没有
No.
你感觉好点儿了吗
Do you feel better?
- 我不是在… - 我有选择
- I'm not trying to… - I had a choice.
要么我脱掉衣服 要么他把你手剁掉
Either I take off my shirt or he would take off your hand.
我听着莫尔在隔壁房间
I just listened to Merle beating the shit out of you.
把你打得半死
in the other room.
我还能怎么做
What could I do?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你滚
Go away.
你知道答案了
You got your answer.
快滚
Now go away.
我们用院子里的铁板加固栅栏
So we'll reinforce this with some metal from the yard.
如果有情况
If anything happens,
我们就躲在后面
we'll just duck.
我希望一切平安
I hope nothing happens.
我怕死枪了
Guns scare the bejesus out of me.
我当年是用玩具枪抢劫的加油站
I robbed a gas station with a toy gun.
甚至没从兜里拿出来
Never even took it out of my pocket.
你不是说奥斯卡才是小偷吗
You said Oscar was the thief.
你进监狱是因为药物问题
That you were in here for pharmaceuticals.
我不想让你们觉得我是个暴徒
Well, I didn't want y'all to think I was a violent man.
懂吧
If you follow me.
那照你所说
So what are you saying?
你进监狱是因为一把玩具枪吗
You're in here for a toy gun?
不 听好
No, listen to this.
第二天警察在我兄弟家里找到我
The next day the cops found me at my brother's house.
我兜里还揣着那把水枪
Still had the water pistol in my pocket.
我对他们发誓
I swore up and down that…
说那是我拥有的唯一武器
that was the only weapon I had,
但他们不相信有蠢蛋
but they said they didn't believe anyone.
用水枪抢加油站还成功了
could be so stupid and get away with it.
所以他们翻遍了我哥哥家
So they turned my brother's house upside down.
最终找到了他的点38手枪
and found his.38.
说「符合描述」
Said it "Matched the description."
罪名成立 「武装抢劫」
There you go. Armed robbery.
说真的 我都不知道这玩意儿怎么用
Tell you the truth, I don't even know how to use this damn thing.
你现在说的都是实话了啊
You're all about the truth now?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am, I am.
子弹已经上满膛
It's fully loaded.
但愿能不要开枪
Let's hope it stays that way.
你真是个好心的女士
You're quite a lady.
我觉得这里像是萨沃齐湾（美国佐治亚州西南方）
Smells to me like the Sawhatchee Creek.
我们还没有那么靠西
We didn't go west enough.
那边有条河 一定是黄衫河（位于美国佐治亚州西部的拉格兰奇）
There's a river down there, it's got to be the Yellow Jacket.
你中风了说胡话吗 老弟
You have a stroke, boy?
我们从来没接近过黄衫河
We ain't never even come close to Yellow Jacket.
我觉得我们没往西走 只是有点靠南
We didn't go west. Just a little bit south. That's what I think.
你知道我怎么想吗
Know what I think?
我虽然失去了一只手
I may have lost my hand,
但你失去了方向感
but you lost your sense of direction.
好吧 走着瞧
Yeah, we'll see.
你想赌什么
What do you want to bet?
什么都不想赌
I don't want to bet nothing.
只是一条河而已
It's just a body of water.
你为什么要把一切都当做比赛
Why's everything got to be a competition with you?
放松点 老弟
Take it easy, little brother.
我只是想找点乐子而已
Just trying to have a little fun here.
没必要小题大做吧
No need to get your panties all in a bundle.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
是的 野生动物发疯吧
Yeah, wild animals getting wild.
- 不 是个婴儿 - 少胡扯
- No, it's a baby. - Oh, come on.
你还不如在我耳朵里撒泡尿
Why don't you just piss in my ear.
然后告诉我下雨了呢
and tell me it's raining, too?
那是一对浣熊在缠绵的声音
That there's the sound of a couple of coons making love, sweet love.
懂我意思吧
Know what I mean?
跳啊
Hey! Jump!
怎么啦
What?
伙计 我才不会为了
Hey, man, I ain't wasting my bullets.
几个素不相识的陌生人
on a couple of strangers that ain't never cooked me a meal.
浪费子弹
or felicitated my piece.
这是我的原则
That's my policy.
放聪明点 学学我 弟弟
You'd be wise to adopt it, brother.
伙计 我是在帮你
Come on, man. I'm trying to help you out.
掩护我
Cover me!
达里尔 交给我
Daryl! I got ya!
走
Go!
讲英语
Speak English.
等等 西语佬
Slow down, beaner.
这可不是表达谢意的方式
That ain't no way to say thank you.
让他们走
Let 'em go.
他们至少也得给我们
The least they can do is give us.
玉米卷饼什么的吧
an enchilada or something, huh?
别紧张 女士
Easy does it, senorita.
没事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
从车里滚出来
Get out of the car.
你不是在对我说话吧 弟弟
I know you're not talking to me, brother.
上车 赶紧离开这里
Get in your car and get the hell out of here.
走 上车
Go! Get in your car!
（黄衫河）
你这是干嘛 用那玩意指着我
The shit you doing, pointing that thing at me?
他们很害怕
They were scared, man.
这帮人太不懂礼数
They were rude is what they were.
也不知道该进贡点东西表示感谢
Rude and they owed us a token of gratitude.
他们不欠我们什么
They didn't owe us nothing.
你当自己是活菩萨拯救苍生吗
You helping people out of the goodness of your heart?
你可能会白白送命的
Even though you might die doing it?
这一套也是瑞克警长教你的吗
Is that something your sheriff Rick taught you?
他们有小孩
There was a baby!
不然你就会不管他们死活了吧
Oh, otherwise you would have just left them to the biters, then?
我回去救你了 可你不在了
Man, I went back for you. You weren't there.
锯掉你手的也不是我 而是你自己
I didn't cut off your hand, neither. You did that.
他们把你拷在屋顶上
Way before they locked you up on that roof.
也是你之前自作自受
You asked for it.
你知道 你知道哪点可笑吗
You know… you know what's funny to me?
你跟瑞克警长现在倒是亲如一家了
You and Sheriff Rick are like this now.
是吗
Right?
我敢打赌
I bet you a penny and a fiddle of gold.
你肯定没告诉过他
that you never told him.
我们原本计划要趁天黑抢劫他们营地的
that we were planning on robbing that camp blind.
可是我们没有
It didn't happen.
那是因为没有我在你身边照应
Yeah, it didn't 'cause I wasn't there to help you.
就像小时候一样吗
What, like when we were kids, huh?
- 那时谁抛下了谁 - 你说什么
- Who left who then? - What?
所以我才失去了一只手吗
Huh? Is that why I lost my hand?
那是因为你是个头脑简单的蠢货
You lost your hand 'cause you're a simple minded piece of shit.
你知道个屁
Yeah? You don't know!
我不知道他也虐待了你
I… I didn't know he was…
是的 他虐待了
Yeah, he did.
就像对你一样
He did the same to you.
所以你才会先离开家
That's why you left first.
我必须走 兄弟
I had to, man.
否则我会忍不住杀了他
I would have killed him otherwise.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
回我现在的家
Back where I belong.
我不能跟你回去
I can't go with you.
之前试图杀死那黑妞的是我
I tried to kill that black bitch.
差点杀死那中国男孩的也是我
Damn near killed the Chinese kid.
他是韩国人
He's Korean.
没区别
Whatever.
反正我没法和你一起回去
Doesn't matter, man. I just can't go with you.
你要知道 走开的人也许是我
You know, I may be the one walking away…
但真正离开的人是你 又一次
but you're the one that's leaving… again.
该死
Damn.
格伦
Glenn?
Glenn!
你不会去伍德伯里吧
You're not going back to Woodbury, are you?
不去
No.
我只是到外面去
I'm just going out there.
- 我和你一起 - 我去就行了
- I'll go with you. - I got it.
你一个人吗
By yourself?
你觉得这是个好主意吗
How can you possibly think that's a good idea?
我不能坐以待毙
I can't just sit on my hands.
之前你就去找个奶粉
You went on a simple formula run.
结果却被打得鼻青脸肿
and got the crap beat out of you.
- 玛姬也被袭击 - 你是说这是我的错
- Maggie was attacked. - Are you saying this is my fault?
- 不是 - 我尽力了
- No. - I did what I could.
我知道
I know you did.
玛姬也是
So does Maggie.
她是这个世界上
She's one of the two people.
我最珍爱的两个人之一
most precious to me in this world.
信任你才把她托付给你
I trust you with her life.
我依然信任你
I still do.
但你这怒气会让你送命的
This rage is going to get you killed.
达里尔走了 瑞克也崩溃了
With Daryl gone and Rick wandering Crazytown,
现在我说的算
I'm the next in charge.
你是要证明什么吗
What are you proving?
她饿了
She's hungry.
你能替我喂喂她吗
Could you help me feed her?
我想去给爸爸弄点吃的
I want to make daddy something to eat.
给你
Here.
像这样拿着奶瓶就行
Just keep the bottle like this.
不然她会胀气
Otherwise she gets gassy.
知道了
Got it.
给你这个
Here's this.
瑞克
Rick.
我一瘸一拐地走这么大老远过来
You know I wouldn't have hobbled all the way down here.
是有要紧的事跟你说
if it wasn't important.
你最近能回来吗
Are you coming back soon?
格伦满腔怒火
Glenn's on the warpath.
他很精明 但他难胜任领袖
Smart as he is, he can't fill your boots.
我担心他会鲁莽行事
I'm afraid he's reckless.
现在正是需要你时候
We need you now more than ever.
好吧 既然你那么担心他
Well, if you're so worried about him,
你来领导吧
you lead.
你在外面做什么
What are you doing out here?
我去…
I've…
我…
I've been…
我在这儿
I've got…
有点事
stuff out here.
Stuff.
你还需要多久
How much longer do you need?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不…
I don't…
有什么我能帮到你的吗
Is there anything I can help you with?
我看到了一些东西
I saw something.
洛莉
Lori.
我看到了洛莉
I saw Lor…
满眼都是洛莉
I'm seeing Lori.
听着 我知道那不是真的她
Look, I know it's not really her.
但她出现一定有原因
But there's got to be a reason.
一定有所深意 你懂吗
It's got to mean something, you know.
电话那头的也是她吗
Was it her on the phone?
是的
Yeah.
还有肖恩
Shane, too.
和其他人
And the town.
现在还会看见他们吗
Do you see them now?
你在寻找他们
You're looking for them.
我在等待
I'm waiting.
等什么
For what?
说不清楚 某事某物
I don't know. Something.
这一切必有答案
There's an answer.
现在 一切可能说不通
I know it doesn't make sense.
但一切总归会有意义的
Well, it does. It can make sense.
在未来 一切都会说得通的
I mean, I think in time it will make sense.
瑞克
Rick…?
进来吧
Come on in.
你需要休息
You need rest.
外面不安全
It's not safe out here.
我不能 我不能
I can't. I can't.
瑞克被压垮了
Stress getting to your man Rick?
这能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
不 当然不
No. Not at all.
监狱里我可见过不少崩溃的人
In here I've seen plenty of dudes crack.
但我不会
But not me.
里面更适合我
I got on better on the inside.
一切更有意义 你懂吗
Things made more sense, you know?
监狱里有规矩
There were rules.
生活更简单
Life was more simple.
你不想念你兄弟吗
Didn't you miss your brother?
我兄弟
My brother?
当然不
Hell, no.
他有经济问题
He had a real money problem.
- 怎讲 - 不借给哥钱
- What kind of problem? - He didn't lend me any.
有一次那小子
One time that son of a bitch…
贝丝
Beth!
- 给 - 快跑
- Here. - Go, go, go!
卡萝尔 快跑
Carol, go!
赫谢尔 快离开那里
Go, Hershel. Get the hell out of there!
- 你没事吧 - 没事 宝贝
- You okay? - Yes. Baby.